Like I said, welcome brothers and
sisters to another Wednesday question
and answer where we open up with the Ten
Commandments that God had written for
the whole world to keep. Brother James.
Yes, sir. And God spake all these words,
saying, I am the Lord thy God, which
have brought thee out of the land of
Egypt, out of the house of bondage. Thou
shalt have no other gods before me. Thou
shalt not make unto thee any graven
image, or any likeness of anything that
is in heaven above, or that is in the
earth beneath, or that is in the water
under the earth. Thou shalt not bow down
thyself to them, nor serve them. For I,
the Lord thy God, am a jealous God,
visiting the iniquity of the fathers,
upon the children unto the third and
fourth generation, of them that hate me,
and showing mercy unto thousands of them
that love me, and keep my commandments.
Thou shalt not take the name of the Lord
thy God in vain, for the Lord will not
hold him guiltless that taketh his name
in vain. Remember the Sabbath day to
keep it holy. Six days shalt thou labor
and do all thy work, but the seventh day
is the Sabbath of the Lord thy God. In
it thou shalt not do any work. Thou nor
thy son, nor thy daughter, thy man's
servant, nor thy maidervant, nor thy
cattle, nor thy stranger that is within
thy gates. For in six days the Lord made
heaven and earth, the sea, and all that
in them is, and rested the seventh day.
Wherefore the Lord blessed the Sabbath
day, and hollowed it. Honor thy father
and thy mother, that thy days may be
long upon the land, which the Lord thy
God giveth thee. Thou shalt not kill.
Thou shalt not commit adultery. Thou
shalt not steal. Thou shalt not bear
false witness against thy neighbor. Thou
shalt not covet thy neighbor's house.
Thou shalt not covet thy neighbor's
wife, nor as man's servant, nor as maid
servant, nor as ox, nor as nor anything
that is thy neighbors. I read Exodus
20:es
1-17. May the Lord add a blessing to the
reading of this word. In Jesus name we
pray. Amen. Amen.
Here on question and answer, you can ask
us a question and we'll answer it
according to the King James Bible. And
if we cannot find the answer, we will
seek further counsel to bring you an
answer at a later time. The questions we
will not answer are the vague and the
long scripture questions as well as
questions of debate. We are not here to
debate. We are here to spread the true
gospel of Jesus. So please be as direct
as possible with your with your
questions so we can be as direct as
possible with our answers out of the
King James Bible. No other Bibles or
books will be acknowledged on this
program. Also, keep in mind that this is
a live stream. So, feel free to send in
your questions that pertain to
everlasting life. We just asking that
you keep them to a two scripture
maximum. But let me introduce to you the
family that's on the panel this evening.
We got brother Julius. Good evening
everybody. Brother Dre. Good evening.
Brother Jerome, rest in peace. Brother
James, good evening everyone. Sister
Deborah, good evening.
Brother Sean, good evening. And we have
the guest caller with us. And I'm
brother Cornell. Sister, let us begin
with our first question of the evening.
Uh, yes, there are several held over
questions that will be answered first
before getting into tonight's Q&A.
Britt Brat says, "I found a
non-alcoholic red wine and wanted to
know if that would be okay or should I
just not partake in the drinking portion
of the Passovers. I also made a vow not
to ever drink again."
All right. So regard
non-alcoholic wine and taking of the
pass over guess call
it. Well if it is
wine then you if it is really wine then
uh uh uh uh you can take it not to take
uh the drinking portion of the uh uh uh
Passover. That's unacceptable.
All that simple. Lord told you that take
he said take this bread and eat it. This
is my flesh and this wine. You know it's
that blood that shed for
you. But
u as far as him not
drinking he say he made a vow not to
drink. Well I hope he said alcohol
because then if he said the vow is the
alcohol not to drink alcohol then that's
one thing you know. But you have to keep
the Passover. So if you can do it by
drinking a wine with no alcohol on and
your vow was correct that you would not
drink any alcoholic beverages, then
you're in good shape. But uh I just
say have to warn you about taking vows
though. Let's go in
Ecclesiastes 5th chapter and read verses
4-6.
The fifth chapter Ecclesiastes 5 and uh
that was verse four and
five and six 4-6 says when thou vowest a
vow unto God defer not to pay it for he
hath no pleasure in fools pay that which
thou hast
vowed. Better is it that thou shouldest
not vow than that thou shouldest vow and
not
pay. Suffer not thy mouth to cause thy
flesh to sin. Neither say thou before
the angel that it was an error.
Wherefore should God be angry at thy
voice and destroy the work of thine
hands?
So now if your vow was not to drink any
alcoholic beverages. Okay. And if this
red wine don't have any alcohol in it,
then you haven't broke your vow.
However, the Lord tell you, you got to
keep this
Passover. And it was bread and wine, not
water and wine, not bread by
itself. So if it's a red non-alcoholic
and you vow not to have alcoholic
beverages, then you might be safe. But
I'mma give you and everybody that that
hear my
voice. Don't ever make a
vow because you just read what the Lord
said. That's a fool that makes a vow and
don't keep it. That's all I have to say.
All right. We hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next one.
Yes. The next question is asked by two
different people. So they will be
combined. Um Zion says, "Could you
explain Psalms 1 verse 5? Does that mean
the wicked won't have to stand before
God on judgment day?" And Stephen Guggis
states the same. He states, "What does
it mean in Psalms 1:es 4 and five when
it says the ungodly shall not stand in
judgment, nor sinners in the
congregation of the righteous, they
won't be judged?"
All right. So, brother Jerome, they got
a little bit in that question, but uh
shed some light, brother. Let's go to
the Psalms chapter one and read it. Read
verse four and five. Okay. Yes. It says,
"The ungodly are not so, but are like
the chief, which the wind driveth away.
Therefore, the ungodly shall not stand
in the judgment, nor sinners in the
congregation of the righteous."
Okay. So um it don't mean that uh the
ungodly or the sinner is not going to
stand
uh before the Lord on judgment day. It
don't mean that you know and if you go
let's go to 2 Corinthians chapter uh
five you
know and read verse
um
10. Okay. 2 Corinthians
5:10 says, "For we must all appear
before the judgment seat of Christ be
that everyone may receive the things
done in his body according to that he
hath done whether it be good or bad."
Yeah. So the ones that have done bad or
evil or wickedness, they gonna be
standing before uh the judgment seat of
Christ just like the ones that have done
righteous. if they weren't in the first
resurrection, per se, or standing before
the Lord um during the white throne
judgment, be you wicked or not, they'll
be standing there. Okay.
Um but I wanted to go to Isaiah the 8th
chapter. Uh cuz it kind of gives you a a
way that that statement shall not stand
in the judgment. It's going to give you
an example how it's defined in that
Psalms 1 um verse 4 and 5. Okay. So,
let's go to Isaiah the 8th chapter and
read verse 9 and 10. Okay. And then we
going to go to um we going to go to
Matthews after that. Uh brother James.
Okay. All right. Go ahead and read when
you get it. Okay. Isaiah 8:es 9 and 10
says, "Associate yourselves, oh ye
people, and ye shall be broken in
pieces, and give ear all ye of far
countries. Guard yourselves, and ye
shall be broken in pieces. Guard
yourselves, and ye shall be broken in
pieces. Take counsel together, and it
shall come to knot. Speak the word, and
it shall not stand, for God is with us."
Yeah. So no matter what they do, God is
with us. So whatever you do, it ain't
going to stand. So you kind of define it
the same way in that Psalms one. When
they stand before the Lord, they ain't
going to be saved like the righteous
going to be saved that's standing um
before the Lord and the white on on
judgment day. The righteous gonna stand
because they gonna be saved. Okay? But
the unrighteous, they not gonna stand.
They not going to be saved. That's what
the shall not stand mean in that verse.
Okay. Now, one more place. Let's go to
Matthew's
25 and we going to read verse 32 through
34. And we going to skip. Okay. Matthew
25 and you said 32.
Yeah. 32 and through 34. Okay. It says,
"And before him shall be gathered all
nations, and he shall separate them one
from another, as a shepherd divideth his
sheep from the goats, and he shall set
the sheep on his right hand, but the
goats on the left. Then shall the king
say unto them on his right hand, come ye
blessed of my father, inherit the
kingdom prepared for you from the
foundation of the world."
[Music]
So you know you got the righteous, they
on the right hand. All right. So now
let's go to verse 41.
Okay. Then shall he say also unto them
on the left hand, depart from me, ye
cursed, into everlasting fire, prepared
for the devil and his angels.
Skip down to verse 46.
and these shall go away into everlasting
punishment, but the righteous into life
eternal. Yeah. So, they stood before the
Lord like like we read in that
Corinthians, you know, but they not
going to be
saved. That's all I got on.
All right. Thank you for that, brother.
Hope that answer that question as we
move on to our next one. Next one. Be
alert as in Zechariah 10 verses 9 and
10. Is this the wilderness the place of
safety? If not, please explain this
scripture.
Zechariah 10 9-10. Is this the
wilderness the place of safety? And if
it is or not, please explain. Brother
Julius,
let's go. Brother James, that's
Zechariah 10. there. Zechariah 10, read
9 and 10.
And I will sow them among the people,
and they shall remember me in far
countries, and they shall live with
their children, and turn again. I will
bring them again also out of the land of
Egypt, and gather them out of Assyria,
and I will bring them into the land of
Gilead and Lebanon, and and place shall
not be found for them. So now let's back
up and read what this is really talking
about. This is not talking about the
wilderness. This is after the
wilderness. Pick it up and read verse
six. And I will strengthen the house of
Judah. And I will save the house of
Joseph. And I will bring them again to
place them, for I have mercy upon them,
and they shall be as though I had not
cast them off. For I am the Lord their
God and will hear them. Now, let's
confirm this. Bringing us back. Let's go
to Isaiah the 11th
chapter. Turn to the book of Isaiah,
chapter 11, my brother. Okay? And we're
going to pick this up at read verse 11
and 12.
And it shall come to pass 11 and 12. And
it shall come to pass in that day that
the Lord that the Lord shall set his
hand again the second time to recover
the remnant of his people which shall be
left from Assyria and from Egypt and
from Pathos and from Kush and from Elam
and from Shinar and from Hamath and from
the islands of the sea. Man, so uh read
verse 12. Go ahead. and he shall set up
an end sign for the nations and shall
assemble the outcast of Israel and
gather together the dispard the
dispersed of Judah from the four corners
of the earth. So this is the second
coming of the Lord. That's what this
Zechariah 10 is talking about. The
second coming of the Lord and the
gathering of his people from all the
places that he has scattered us that he
has scattered us because Israel is going
to be gathered. You could read Ezekiel
the 36th chapter at verse 24 and 25 and
then verse 28 on your own it tells you
the same thing. This is the second
coming of the Lord and the gathering of
his people from Israel uh after the
wilderness cuz when the Lord take you to
the wilderness he is not coming when he
come right back into Jerusalem. He got
to purge out the rebels in the
wilderness. Go ahead. That that's all I
got Cornell.
Right. Thank you for that. Hope that
answered your question. As we move on to
our next question, next question. Glenn
Sirius wants you to explain Revelation
17 10 and 11.
All right. Explanation on Revelation 17.
Let's go there, brother
James. Read that verse 10 11. Dealing
with some kings here and a guest caller.
We'll take it from there. Okay.
Revelation 17 10 and 11 says, "And there
are seven kings, five are fallen, and
one is, and the other is not yet come.
And when he cometh, he must continue a
short space. And the beast that was and
is not, even he is the eighth, and is of
the seventh, and goeth into pdition."
Okay, this is talking about the king,
the guys that tried to restore the Roman
Empire. We'll go and and and we'll go
and show you three of them was was
plucked up by the roots. In other words,
uh this little horn which represent the
pope had them removed because uh he
couldn't control them. Let's go into uh
uh let's go into Daniel the 7th chapter.
We're going to read 1 through 3.
Okay. Daniel 7:es 1-3 says, "In the
first year of Belshazzar, king of
Babylon, Daniel had a dream and visions
of his head upon his bed. Then he wrote
the dream and told the sum of the
matters. Daniel spake and said, "I saw
in my vision by night, and behold, the
four winds of of the heaven strove upon
the great sea, and four great beasts
came up from the sea, diverse one from
another."
Now the sea represent the people. And
these four men, winds of heaven, and
these four great beasts, that's talking
about people. The first one was Babylon.
The second one was Neo Persia. The third
one was uh uh uh Greece. And the fourth
one is Rome. And Rome is not like the
rest of them. They serve their time and
went on. But but Rome is going to come
down through the years with men trying
to restore them. And these men are
defined as as horns. So now let's skip
right on down to verse seven and pick
this up at at at Rome.
Verse 7 says, "After this, I saw in the
night visions, and behold, a fourth
beast, dreadful and terrible, and strong
exceedingly, and it had great iron
teeth. It devoured and break in pieces,
and stamped the residue with the feet of
it, and it was diverse from one from all
the beasts that were before it." And it
had 10 horns.
Now, this now this beast had 10 horns.
that these 10 horns, they were they
didn't come up at at the same time. This
talking about down through the ages, but
what's going to happen to the first
three horns that tried to restore the
Roman Empire. Keep reading. I considered
the horns, and behold, there came up
among them another little horn, before
whom there were three of the first horns
plucked up by the roots. And behold, in
this horn were eyes like the eyes of a
man and a mouth speaking great things.
Now that is that horn represent the
pope. And the three horns that was
plucked up was the Oshots, the Vandals,
and the Hurai by the roots. You don't
never hear about them no more. And so
when these three horn was plucked up,
there was seven left. And these are
talking represent men that tried to
restore the Roman Empire. So now
Revelation said five are
fallen and I'm saying right now six are
fallen. The last one was uh uh Bonito
Mussolini and all of them tried to do
the same thing that was to restore the
Holy Roman Empire.
So now six of four and then and and and
and we have one more to come and whoever
he is he is going to
restore the Roman Empire and that and
but it's not under is not going to be
under the name of the Roman Empire. All
of them had to all of them had to sign a
treaty that's called the treaties of
Rome. But the modern day name now is the
European Union. Now, whoever whatever
man that rises and start and and take
and and elect be elected to the head of
the European Union, he is going to be of
the seven, but he is going to be the
eight man that rule the eight head that
ruled over the the uh uh uh gentile
dynasty. So, what you got? You got uh uh
uh Nebuchadnezzar as one head. Uh
Babylon rather that's one head. Then Meo
Persian count as one head. Then they had
the Greek which was four heads that took
over there six. And then you had Rome
was seven. Now when this next guy take
over the European when this guy take
over the European Union he is going to
be the eighth one to rule this gentile
dynasty. But he going to come from among
the
seven. And uh uh these seven are going
to go against Jesus when he
come. Now if you really really want to
get a a comprehensive understanding of
this, then you can buy the book that the
Israel of God sale is called the four
winds of heaven. and they will break
this down and show you through prophecy
and history who they are and what they
supposed to do. That's all I have to
say.
Hope that answered your question there
as we move on to our next one. Next one.
Be alert as the burdens of nations like
Moab, Egypt, Edom, Caldings, Arabia,
Syria in the Bible. Is this the lands
that will be returned back to Israel
when Jesus returns?
All right. The burdens of the nations
they asking about. Guess call them.
Well, you know, he but he said, uh, uh,
you know, are these the lands that will
be returned back to Israel when Jesus
come? Well, the whole thing is these
lands never belong to
Israel. So now, Israel is scattered
among these people and they going to be
returned from among these lands, but
they going to be returned to Judah and
Israel. Let's go into Isaiah 66.
read 15 and 16 then we going to skip.
Okay, that is Isaiah 66 verses 15 and 16
which says for behold the Lord will come
with fire and with his chariots like a
whirlwind to render his anger with fury
and his rebuke with flames of fire. For
by fire and by his sword will the Lord
plead with all flesh, and the slain of
the Lord shall be many.
Now, this is when the Lord come. Jesus
going to kill a whole lot of people.
Skip down to verse 19 and go ahead. And
I will set a sign among them. And I will
send those that escape of them unto the
nations to Tarses, Pull, and Lud that
draw the bow to Tibal and Jan to the
isles of far off that have not heard my
fame, neither have seen my glory. And
they shall declare my glory among the
Gentiles.
Go ahead. And they shall bring all your
brethren for an offering unto the Lord
out of all nations upon horses and in
chariots and litters and upon mules and
upon swift beasts to my holy mountain
Jerusalem, sayaeth the Lord, as the
children of Israel bring an offering in
a clean vessel into the house of the
Lord. Go ahead. and I will also take of
them for priests and for Levites,
sayaeth the Lord.
Now, so now they are going to be
returned from these lands and all lands
wherever Israel is scattered and they're
going to be taken back to
Israel as after the Lord has returned.
That's why he said he going to set his
hand the second time recover the
children of Israel like somebody read
already in the 11th chapter of Isaiah.
So now these land don't belong to them.
These lands he he going to recover them
from and take them all back to the land
of Israel. That's all I have to say. All
right. Hope that answers your question
as we move on to our next one. Moving
on. Jennifer Love asks, "Is there a
certain menu for the feast of unleaven
bread or is it different for each
location?"
All right, Dre. Is there a certain menu
or is it up to each location?
Yeah, the feast committee. The feast
committee uh has a menu that you choose
from to uh to make whatever foods that's
on the list to make for the feast of
unleavened bread. So,
um, at this point, the locations, those
that head up the feast committee, they
set the menu and it's according to that
location. That's all I got. That's all I
got. All right. Thank you for that,
brother. As we move on to our next
question, moving on. Cool. Blue
says in 1 John 5 verse7 it claims the
Holy Ghost is part of God as in three
became one. I need more insight because
I know the Holy Ghost isn't part of the
Godhead.
All right, brother Julius, can you give
a little more insight to that question?
Uh yes. Let's go. Let's go to that first
John. This is a great erroneous
teaching, a teaching and a doctrine of
great error. Let's look at what the
Bible is saying because this is where
the origin of your trinity comes from. 1
John 5 and 7.
For there are three that bear record in
heaven, the Father, the Word, and the
Holy Ghost. And these three are one. Did
it say that these three are God? No. Are
one? These three are one. They are one
in
agreement. For they are three that bear
record in heaven. The father, the son,
the which is the uh the word which is
the son, Jesus, the Christ, and the holy
ghost. Let's look at uh Revelation the
first chapter. Let's get all three of
them. Revelation and we going to read
verse one and verse two.
Revelation 1, James verse one and verse
two.
The revelation of Jesus Christ, what
they call the trinity, sisters and
brothers, is uh not uh it is not written
in the Bible. The word trinity is not
written in the Bible. That came from the
Catholic church fathers at the council
of Na and 3:25. All of them was Catholic
bishops and archbishops. Revelation 1
and one. Go ahead, brother. the
revelation of Jesus Christ which God
that's one go ahead which God gave unto
him that's the father that's two go
ahead to show unto his servants things
which must shortly come to pass and he
sent and signified it by his angel unto
his servant John that is the angel the
angel of his presence which which is the
Holy Ghost the Father, the Son, and the
angel of his presence, which is the Holy
Ghost, who did what in verse two, who
bear record of the word of God, and of
the testimony of Jesus Christ, and of
all things that he saw. So therefore,
sisters and brothers, they agree in one,
but it's only two in the Godhead. Let me
show you what I'm talking about real
quick. Let's go James to Romans, the
first chapter. Let's
put a a a good witness of that. Romans
chapter one and let's do us the
account. Let's do us account. Indulge me
for a second. Romans 1 and give me verse
one quickly.
All a servant of Jesus Christ called to
be an apostle separated unto the gospel
of God. And what did Paul say in verse
seven? Let's do us account now. To all
that be in Rome, beloved of God, called
to be saints, grace to you and peace
from God our Father and the Lord and the
Lord Jesus Christ.
Two, two, sisters and brothers. 1
Corinthians
1. 1 Corinthians
1. And when you get there, brother, read
verse two.
unto the church of God, which is at
Corinth, to them that are sanctified in
Christ Jesus, called to be saints, with
all that in every place call upon the
name of Jesus Christ our Lord, both
theirs and ours. So now read verse
three. Grace be unto you, and peace from
God our father, and from the and from
the Lord Jesus Christ.
two. Now, if the angel is God, let's go
to Hebrews, the first chapter, and this
my last scripture. Hebrews chapter 1,
and let's look at what Hebrews 1
said. Let me see if this is what I
want.
Yeah. Pick it up at verse 7.
And of the angels he saith, who maketh
his angels spirits and his men? Back up.
Back up and read verse five. I'm sorry.
Okay. For unto which of the angels said
he at any time, thou art my son, this
day have I begotten thee? And again, I
will be to him a father, and he shall be
to me a son. Exactly. And so he told you
to which of the angels said he at any
time, thou my son. Never said that. He
only said that to the one that became
the Christ. Jesus the Christ. Sisters
and brothers. So it's only two in the
Godhead. That's all I got. The father
and the son. They occupy the title
called God. And Jesus sits on the right
hand of the father. And nobody sits on
his left hand. That's all I got.
All right. Thank you for that, brother.
As we move on to our next question. Next
question. Israel longar wants you to
explain
Psalms 129 vers 6 and 7.
All right. Why don't we go to the Psalms
129 6 and
7 and when you get there brother James
go ahead read it and Gus caller will
take it from there. Psalm 129:6 and 7
says, "Let them be as the grass upon the
housetops, which wither before it
groweth up, wherewith the mower fillth
not his hand, nor he that bindeth sheav
into his bosoms."
Now, you know, we need we need to start
a little let's let's let's why don't we
just start at verse one and read down.
Okay.
Psalm 129 and1 says, "Many a time have
they afflicted me from my youth. May
Israel now say, many a time have they
afflicted me from my youth, yet they
have not prevailed against
me." The plowers plowed upon my back,
they made long their furrows. The Lord
is righteous. He hath cut us under the
cords of the wicked. Let them all be
confounded and turned back that hate
Zion. Let them be as the grass upon the
housetops, which wither of for it
groweth up, wherewith the moore fillth
not his hand, nor he that bind the sheav
his bosom.
All it's really saying is that all these
people that them beat up and destroyed
and hurted
Israel when the Lord
come when he said that uh let them be uh
uh saying that uh uh the wicked saying
about the wicked let them be cast
down or be cut down like you do grass.
In other words, to put it short, let all
these people that have abused Israel be
destroyed. That's it. Plain and simple.
All
right, thank you for that. As we move on
to our next question, next question. Uh,
Stephen Goog says, "Someone gave my
twoyear-old daughter $50 for her
birthday. Do we have to pay tithe on
that increase? Do we pay tithe on the
increase of our children?
Yeah, you should because you trying to
train up your child in the way that they
should go and whatever age that they are
able to learn, you should get right on
it. But let's go to um because some
people even say you don't have to pay
tithe, period. But let's go to Hebrews
7. Hebrews 7.
And let's see what Abraham
did. Hebrews 7:1. When you get there,
brother, go ahead. For this Melchisedc,
king of Salem, priest of the most high
God, who met Abraham, returning from the
slaughter of the kings, and blessed
him, to whom also Abraham gave a tenth
part of all, first part of a tenth part
of all, and we'll we'll cover that, too.
Go ahead.
first being by interpretation king of
righteousness and after that also king
of Salem which is king of peace
without father without mother without
dissent having neither beginning of days
nor end of life but made like unto the
son of god abideth a priest continually.
So you see Abraham, he paid a tenth part
of all the spoils to the God of
righteousness. And that was to set a
table for everybody down through the
generations that you ought to pay tithes
on your increase. Go ahead. Verse four.
Now consider how great this man was,
unto whom even the patriarch Abraham
gave the tenth of the spoils. All right,
so he gave the tenth of the spoils. Turn
over to Genesis 28. Genesis 28.
And let's see what Jacob did here.
Genesis
28. And Isaac paid tithes, too. We just
going to deal with Jacob. And then one
more verse. Go ahead, read um pick it
up. Verse 20. Go ahead.
And Jacob vowed a vow, saying, If God
will be with me, and will keep me in
this way that I go, and will give me
bread to eat, and reignment to put on,
so that I come again to my father's
house in peace, then shall the Lord be
my God. And this stone which I have set
for a pillar shall be God's house. And
of all that thou shalt give me, I will
surely give the tenth unto thee. All
right, the tenth unto thee. So even
Jacob also, let's go to last place.
Proverbs 3. Proverbs 3. Because you was
asking, you know, because someone gave
your two-year-old daughter, you know,
she very young, $50 for her birthday,
but they gave it to you. So therefore,
it was increased for you in regards to
her. But read that verse uh nine and 10
for me. Go ahead. Honor the Lord with
thy substance and with the first fruits
of all thine increase. Of all thy
increase. Everything come into your hand
on the good side because there's a money
that the Lord say he don't want. But in
this case when you asking about your
daughter just showing that it came into
your hand that was a part of your
increase for your daughter. Go ahead.
What's the blessing behind intent? So
shall thy barns be filled with plenty,
and thy presses shall burst out with new
wine. All right? So it's a blessing
behind, you know, paying your tithes.
Even for those that say you don't have
to, they incorrect with that. But if
they' have gave you, you know, $100,
then yeah, you should have paid $10 a
tithes on that and so forth and so on.
So yeah, that was an increase for you.
So you pay the five and you still got 45
for your daughter. And that's all I
got. All right, we hope that answered
your question as we move on to our next
one. Moving on. Ha J Israel
says, "Some believe that wine is not to
be drunken on Passover because that's
not what they actually had consumed."
Can you break that down also? Can you
break down if we can eat lamb?
All right, Julius. So, regarding this
Passover, can you shed some light,
brother? Absolutely. Let's answer that
second question first. You could eat
anything you want to eat, but when it
comes to the Passover,
uh the Lord told you the bread and the
wine. The bread and the wine. Now, you
got some people who still kill the lamb.
You I hope they find out if it's if it's
a male and they keep it up uh on the
10th day and on the 14th day and they
got to be perfect. You don't know if
none of that. So, we don't need to do
that uh the uh don't eat the lamb no
more. And we going to show you why. We
going to show you why. Let's answer this
this first question first. Let's go to 1
Corinthians the 5th
chapter. 1 Corinthians
5 because Jesus shed his blood and every
all that uh the bitter earth all that
pointed to him. All of it. 1 Corinthians
5 and 7 James when you get it. Go ahead
brother. Purge out therefore the old
leaven that ye that ye may be a new lump
as ye are unleavenvened. For even Christ
our passover is sacrificed for us.
Though Christ is our
Passover, he took the place of that lamb
because he was the lamb, even a lamb
slave from the foundation of the world.
Now they're saying uh repeat the
question there with the uh first part.
Yes.
Uh hang some believe that wine is not to
be drunken on Passover because that's
not what they actually had consumed.
Wow, that's an
assumption. It don't matter what you
think and how you feel. What do the book
say? Let's go and see. Let's go to Luke
the 7th
chapter. Cuz some people talking about
it's grape juice. No. Grapes come from
what is the definition of a wine press?
A wine press is a press in which grapes
are squeezed into making wine. That's
aged
grapes. Luke 7, we going to read verse
28 and skip Luke 7-28. James Luke, I 28.
Go ahead, brother. For I say unto you,
among those that are born of woman,
there is not a greater prophet than John
the Baptist. But he but he that is least
in the kingdom of God is greater than
he. Man, verse 33, skip down to verse.
You're talking about John the Baptist.
This is Jesus talking about John the
Baptist. Go ahead. For John the Baptist
came neither eating bread nor drinking
wine. And you say he had a devil. He
wasn't eating. He came eating bread nor
drinking wine, not grape juice. And you
say he got a devil. But what? 34. The
son of man is come eating and drinking.
And ye say, "Behold a gluttonous man."
And a wine
bibber. A grape juice. A wine bber. A
wine bibber. In other words, today we
call it a wine head. Go ahead. A friend
of publicans and sinners. Now, now let's
go to Matthew the 26th
chapter. See, people assume the book is
what the book
says. Matter of fact, that was the first
miracle that Jesus did turn water to
wine. Yeah. Matthew 26. We're going to
read 26 and 29. Brother James, Matthew
26 and 26. Go ahead, brother. But I say
unto you, I will not drink henceforth of
this fruit of the vine until that day
when I drink it new with you in my
father's kingdom. Talking about the
talking about wine. Go ahead. That's the
fruit of the vine. Wine. Couple them
grapes. Go ahead. And when they had sung
in him, they went out into the mount of
olives. Then Jesus saith unto them, "All
ye shall be offended because of me this
night." For it is and read verse 26.
Okay? And as they were eating, Jesus
took bread and blessed it and break it
and break it and gave it to the
disciples and said, "Take, eat. This is
my body."
And he took And he took the cup and gave
thanks and gave it to them, saying,
"Drink ye all of it. For this is my
blood of the new testament, which is
shed for many for the remissions of
sins." Because the wine represents the
shed blood of Jesus, sisters and
brothers. It was wine in the cup. And
I'm going show you that it was wine in
the cup because Jesus came in full
fields and picked up some tools that he
had under another name. Let's go to my
last place, Genesis the 14th chapter.
Genesis chapter
14. This why this why we let the Bible
do the speaking. There's no room for
assumptions. What we feel, how we think.
Genesis 14 and 14. When you get it,
James, read
it. And when Abram heard that his
brother was taken captive, he armed his
trained servants, born in his own house,
318, and pursued them unto Dan. We're
talking about during the time of these
kings that fought, these Hidic kings
that fought. Skip down to 16 and we
going to 18. Go ahead, brother. And he
brought back all the goods and also
brought again his brother Lot and his
goods and the women also and the people.
And the king of Sodom went out to meet
him after his return from the slaughter
of Chedoram and of the kings that were
with him at the valley of Shva, which is
the king's dale. But who else was there?
And Mechisedc, king of Salem, brought
forth, king of Salem. It was called
Salem at that time, but it's Jerusalem.
Go ahead. Brought forth bread and wine.
Bread and grape. Bread and wine. Bread
and wine. Jesus picked up his old tools
in the New Testament, the same wells
that he originated with under the name
of Mechisedc. And did what? and he was
the priest of the most high God. So it
was wine in the cup and Jesus drank so
much that they call him a wine
bibber. That's all I got, Cornell.
All right. Thank you, brother. Cuz we
know that bread and wine was with Abram
and with um the God of righteousness.
Right. That's right. If you going to eat
the
lamb, if you going to do wrong, do wrong
right.
is our Passover.
Brother, I want I want to say this.
Anybody that's still killing the lamb,
do not believe
in Jesus. That's point blank. All all
that simple.
All right. So, we hope that your light
comes on so that you can see the light.
Hope that answered your question as we
continue to move on. And Sister Deborah,
as we go into new territory, I believe,
can we do it with a time check? Yes, the
time is
8:17. We are now into tonight's Q&A for
April the 9th,
2025. Daughter of Judah has several
questions. Uh her first one
is in Genesis
1 11. On the third day when God created
the trees and plants and then declared
that all was good, did that include the
tree of the knowledge of good and evil?
If not, who created the tree and when?
All right. So, let's open this question
up to the panel and it starts off with
Genesis 1 and 11.
Yes. All right. And then um go right
ahead guest call.
I have it. Go read it. Okay. Genesis
1:11 says, "And God said, let the earth
bring forth grass, the herb yielding
seed, and the fruit tree yielding fruit
after his kind, whose seed is in itself
upon the earth." And it was so.
Okay. Okay. So that that uh uh that was
so that was that was the way it went.
But now uh he also asked a question
where he said and God formed man. I mean
say God created the man. Skip down and
read that on
the ver verse
uh what verse again sir?
Get right down to it. That's uh uh 27.
27. Read it. See what it says. So God
created man in his own image. In the
image of man God created he him. Male
and female created he them. Uh-huh. He
read. And God blessed them. And God said
unto them, "Be fruitful and multiply,
and replenish the earth, and subdue it,
and have dominion over the fish of the
sea, and over the fowl of the air, and
over every living thing that moveth upon
the earth.
Go ahead. And God said, "Behold, I have
given you every herb bearing seed, which
is upon the face of all the earth, and
every tree, and which is the fruit of a
tree yielding seed, to you it shall be
for me."
Okay, now we going keep reading. and to
every beast of the earth, and to every
fowl of the air, and to everything that
creepeth upon the earth, wherein there
is life, I have given every green herb
for meat, and it was
so. Go ahead. And and God saw that he
had made, and behold, it was very good,
and the evening and the morning were the
sixth day.
Go ahead. Chapter two. Chapter. Yes,
that's the end of the chapter.
Chapter
two and one says, "Thus the heavens and
the earth were finished, and all the
host of them. And on the seventh
day, that's the key right
there. Thus the heaven and the earth
were finished, and all the host of them,
man was also a part of the earth." Okay,
go ahead and read. And on the seventh
day, God ended his work which he had
made. And he rested on the seventh day
from all his work which he had made. He
said, "Now he ended his work." End mean
there ain't nothing else left. Isn't
that correct? Right. Yes, sir. Go ahead.
And God blessed the seventh day and
sanctified it because that in it he had
rested from all his work which God
created and made.
Now, he kept telling you he had rested.
He was through. So, now when you start
this this fourth verse, I want you to
pay attention how it starts out. Verse
four, go ahead. These are the
generations of the heavens and of the
earth when they were created in the day
that the Lord ga and the Lord God made
the earth and the heavens.
Now, pay attention. These are the
generation of the heavens and of the
earth when they were
created in the day that the Lord God
made the earth and the heavens. So he
started. So now the first chapter tell
you that God created it and the second
chapter tell you how he created it. God
created man the male and female. How did
he do it?
He formed them. God formed them out of
the dust of the ground and breathed into
their nostrils the breath of life. The
first chapter tell you what God did.
Second chapter tell you how he did it.
Okay. So now that wasn't on the eighth
day that was on the sixth day or the
seventh day he had completed. Now, as
far as the uh uh uh tree of the
knowledge uh uh of go and go ahead on
read seven. We're going to look at these
couple of trees here. Go ahead. Okay.
You want me to finish at verse five or
you want me to skip down? Verse seven.
Okay. Verse seven says, "And the Lord
God formed man of the dust of the
ground, and breathed into his nostrils
the breath of life, and man became a
living soul."
Uh-huh. And the Lord God
planted And the Lord God planted a
garden eastward in Eden, and there he
put the man whom he had formed. And out
of the ground made the Lord God to grow
every tree that is pleasant to the
sight. And good for food. The tree of
life.
Pay attention. Good for food.
Punctuation. These are for food. But now
he going to speak of two other trees. Go
ahead. The tree of life also in the
midst of the garden and the tree of
knowledge of good and evil.
Now why do he have to if they were some
regular trees, then why would he have to
talk to them special? because they are
not regular trees. The tree of the
knowledge of good and evil, that is
Satan, the devil. The same tree of the
knowledge of good and evil is called the
serpent. Now, let's go and see who this
serpent is. Let's go into Revelation the
12th chapter.
Revelation chapter
12 and we're going to start
reading and we're going to read verse 9.
12 and 9. Okay. Revelation 12 and9 says,
"And the great dragon was cast out, that
old serpent called the devil and Satan,
which deceiveth the whole world. He was
cast out into the earth, and his angels
were cast out with him.
So now that servant, the tree of the
nun, he's the one that talked to Adam
and Eve and and uh uh he informed them
of things that God wasn't ready for him
to be informed at that time. Especially
they sex sexual uh uh uh difference
because that's why they made them
aprons of
leaves. So the same uh uh uh so the tree
of knowledge, good and evil, and the
serpent is one and the same. Satan, the
devil. You have a lot of titles, but as
far as the tree of life, we're going to
see about that. Let's uh uh
uh let's read the uh
uh Genesis
3 and we going to read from 1 to 3, then
we going to skip. Okay. Genesis 3 1-3
says, "Now the serpent was more subtle
than any beast of the field which the
Lord God had made. And he said unto the
woman, "Ya hath God said, Ye shall not
eat of every tree of the garden?" And
the woman said unto the serpent, "We may
eat of the fruit of the trees of the
garden, but of the fruit of the tree
which is in the midst of the garden. God
has said, Ye shall not eat of it,
neither shall ye touch it, least ye
die."
Now that tree is Satan, the devil, which
is also called the serpent. We gave you
all his titles. Okay. So now because man
uh uh ate of the tree, skip down to
verse 17 and look what the Lord did. He
he called sinners on man. Verse 17.
And unto Adam he said, because thou has
hearkened unto the voice of thy wife,
and has eaten of the tree of which I
commanded thee, saying, Thou shalt not
eat of it. Cursed is the ground for thy
sake, and sorrow shalt thou eat of it
all the days of thy life.
So now what did they eat? They ate the
Jose will tell you that they ate the
fruit of
lies. That's like uh uh uh and Jesus
tell you in in sixth chapter of St. John
when he say eat my flesh and drink my
blood. And they said and his disciples
said this is a hard saying. He said the
flesh profited nothing. The words that I
speak unto you, they are spirit and they
are life. In other words, he tell them
to eat my word. But now, since Adam and
Eve did that and God called the death
center on Adam on Adam and Eve, skip
down to verse 24 and see what the Lord
did concerning the tree of life. Verse
24.
So he drove out the man and he placed at
the east of the garden of Eden cherubams
and a flaming sword which turned every
way to keep the way of the tree of life.
See first he told him look man has
become as wanted us to know good and
evil. Now unless he put forth his hand
and eat of the tree of life and live
forever. God put the man out the garden.
So he drove the man out the garden and
he and he put share of angels east of
Eden to protect what?
Tree of life. Tree of life.
Okay. So now wherever this tree of life
is, then you going to find these chair
of angels there. Isn't that correct?
Right. Yes, sir. So let's give you an
example. Let's go into Psalm chapter 99
and read verse one. There you go. Okay.
Psalm 99 and1 says, "The Lord reignth.
Let the people tremble. He siteth
between the cherubams. Let the earth be
moved."
So why is it that he sit between the
cherub? Because he is the tree of life.
And the lord put cherub angels around
him to protect the way of the tree of
life. So the tree of life was Jesus fear
of the knowledge of good and
evil. And the servant is Satan, the
devil. That's all I have to say. All
right. So, we hope that that helped to
shed some light for you as we move on to
our next question. Yes. Um she also has
uh another qu uh two questions in one
which is when I was attending a COG
church I was baptized under water in the
name of God the father Jesus the son and
the holy spirit so I don't know why she
put that in but she wants to know if I
am not a member of
IOG can I still attend in your Passover
service. And then she asks, "What did
Paul mean in Romans 10 verse 4?" So she
wants to know, "Can you attend the
Passover service?" And the other
question, what did Paul mean in Romans
10 verse4?
All right, let's open that up to the P.
Go read it.
Okay. Romans 10:4 says, "For Christ is
the end of the law for righteousness to
everyone that believeth."
Okay? You want to find out what the Lord
is talking about, go to Hebrews the 10th
chapter and read verse one.
Hebrews the 10th chapter verse 1 says,
"For the law having a shadow of good
things to come and not the very image of
the things can never with those
sacrifices which they offered yearby
year continually make the comers there
unto perfect."
So now that's the law that Christ ended
the law of animals
sacrifice. And why is it that they
couldn't make the come as they are
perfect? Skip down to verse four and
continue. For it is not possible that
the blood of bulls and of goats should
take away sins.
Wherefore, wherefore when he cometh into
the world, he saith, sacrifice an
offering thou wouldth not, but a body
has thou prepared me?
So now the reason that they uh so when
Jesus when he said that this they
couldn't they couldn't make the come
perfect this is talking about the
sacrifice sacrificial law he said then
you prepared a body for me why did Jesus
need a body because Jesus was God he
couldn't die so he needed a flesh and
blood body that could
die but keep reading let's see what what
happened ahead in burnt offerings and
sacrifices for sin Thou hast had no
pleasure.
[Music]
Then said I lo Then said I, Lo, I come
in the volume of the book, it is written
of me to do thy will, oh God. Go ahead.
Above when he said, sacrifice and
offering and burnt offerings and
offering for sin, thou wouldest not,
neither has pleasure therein, which are
offered by the law. which are offered by
the law. What law? The law of animal
sacrifice. That's the one that Jesus in.
But keep reading. Then said he, "Lo, I
come to do thy will, oh God. He taketh
away the first that he may establish the
second."
By the by the which will we are we are
sanctified through the offering of the
body of Jesus Christ once for all.
So now once for all. Unless you are
sanctified. Now what happened to an
animal sacrifice? Skip down and read
verse 18.
Now where remission of these is, there
is no more offering for sin.
So now Christ ended the law, but is the
law of animal sacrifice. That's why you
terminated, not God's commandment. What
was the rest of that to that question?
Uh the rest of it was uh she's not a
member of IOG. So can she attend the
Passover service?
Okay, let's go in Exodus the 12th
chapter and we should start uh uh go and
uh uh
uh go and uh
uh where is I think it's around 38 uh
somewhere where it say this is the
ordinance of the Passover
43 43 what is it? Yes. Okay. 43
Okay. Exodus 12 and verse 43 says, "And
the Lord said unto Moses and Aaron, this
is the ordinance of the Passover. There
shall no stranger eat
thereof, but every man's servant that is
bought for money when thou had
circumcised him, then shall he eat
thereof."
Okay, you can skip down again after that
a little further. Say, "If a stranger
will eat the Passover," go ahead. Verse
48. And when a stranger shall shall
sjjoin with thee, and will keep the
Passover to the Lord, let all his males
be circumcised, and then let him come
near and keep it, and he shall be as one
that is born in the land, for no
uncircumcised person shall eat thereof.
So now, those are the only one, that's
the only one that
prohibited from eating the Passover. So
being that you are a woman, you don't
need to be
circumcised. So you can eat of it. But
you spoke also that you was baptized in
in
what? Okay. She was baptized uh in the
ca uh in the COG church
uh in underwater in the name of God the
Father, Jesus the Son, and the Holy
Spirit.
Okay, let's go into Matthew the 28th
chapter and look at that
and we're going to start where
Jesus told the apostles and he said and
he told them go into all the world
preach the gospel. Verse 19. 19.
Okay, read it.
Go ye therefore and teach all nations,
baptizing them in the name of the
father, and of the son and of the holy
ghost. Now nobody pays attention to when
he say in the name of the father, the
son and the holy ghost. So you have to
call a name over them and all of them
have to have and and that name have to
cover every one of them.
So Jesus told you he came in his
father's
name. And read that. Somebody find it
and read it right quick. That's John
five.
Read it. Five and what? What? That 39.
Uh let's see. No, hold on.
Uh that is
same time. Yeah. 43. 43. 43.
Yeah. St. John 5 and 40 St. John 5 and
43 says, "I am come in my father's name,
and ye receive me not. If another shall
come in his own name, him ye will
receive."
Now, he said he come in his father's
name, didn't he? Yep. Okay, sir. Now, he
said he said he going to pray to the
father and he going to send you the Holy
Ghost in whose name? Could somebody find
that right quick?
the name that he came to that he came in
in Luke the first
chapter. What now? What he said is uh uh
I will pray to the is uh speed and I go
but I go I go the Holy Ghost won't come
but if I go he'll come. And he said and
he will pray to the father and the
father will send you the holy
ghost in his name. John 14. John 14.
John 14. Okay. Read it because I want to
read these things so this will
understand.
Okay. Okay. Read it. John 14 and pick it
up. Pick it up at the uh 15. Okay. It
says, "If ye love me, keep my
commandments, and I will pray the
Father, and he shall give you another
comforter, that he may abide with you
forever. Even the Spirit of truth, whom
the world cannot receive, because it
seeth him not, neither knoweth him, but
ye know him, for he dwelleth with you,
and shall be in you. I will not leave
you comfortless. I will come to
you yet a little while and the world
seeth me no more but ye see me because I
live ye live ye shall live
also. At that day ye shall know that I
am in the my father and ye in me and I
in you. He that hath my commandments and
keepeth them, he is that loveth me. And
he that loveth me shall be loved of my
father, and I will love him, and will
manifest myself to him.
Is
it the father?
He'll send you the holy ghost in my
name. That's what I'm looking for. John
16 and 7. Okay. Okay. That's what I'm
looking for. Read it. It says,
"Nevertheless, I tell you the truth. It
is expedient for you that I go away. or
if I go not away, the comforter will not
come unto you. But if I depart, I will
send him unto you.
I still in here, he will send the
comforter in my name. And verse 26 and
uh John 14 Yeah. 14 John 14 and 26 says
but when the comforter has come whom I
will send unto you from the father even
the spirit of truth which proceedth from
the father he shall testify of me
John
14:26 but the com yeah John oh okay I'm
sorry but but the comforter which is the
Holy Ghost whom the father will send in
my name he shall teach you all things
and bring all things to your remembrance
whatsoever I have said unto you.
Okay. Now Jesus say come in his father's
name. Yep. And then he going to pray to
the father and he going to send you the
comforter which is the holy ghost in his
name. So that's the name you want to
baptize people in. Now we go into acts
the second chapter. Let's see if we can
show
you when it men and brethren, what shall
we do? That's Acts 2 38.
Huh? Acts 2 and 38.
Uh-huh. Go and read it. It says, "Then
Peter said unto them, repent and be
baptized every one of you in the name of
Jesus Christ for the remission of sins."
That's in the name of Jesus. Now, that's
that's Peter. Now let's go and see what
Paul said. Let's go in Acts the 19th
chapter and start reading at verse one.
Okay. Acts 19 and 1
says, "And it came to pass that while
Apollos was at Corinth, Paul having
passed through the upper coast came to
Ephesus and finding certain disciples,
he said unto them, have ye received the
Holy Ghost since ye believed?" And they
said unto him, We have not so much as
heard whether there be an Holy Ghost.
And he said unto them, Unto what then
were ye baptized? And they said, Unto
John's baptism. Then said Paul, John
verily baptized with the baptism of
repentance, saying unto the people that
they should believe on him which should
come after him that is on Christ Jesus.
When they heard this, they were baptized
in the name of the Lord Jesus.
Now, so that so Jesus came in the
father's name that mean the father name
was Jesus. Yes. That's why the name
heaven then and and because he came in
his father named that name that mean
that he his name was Jesus. Then he sent
you the holy spirit in this case was an
angel. He came in his name. So now, so
he called his name Jesus. That's why
when you baptize in the name of Jesus,
you baptize in the name of the father
and in the name of the son and in the
name of the holy spirit which came in
the name of Jesus. So if they didn't say
I baptize you in the name of Jesus, then
you need to get baptized again.
That's all I say about all that. Yeah,
that is correct. And uh sister Deborah
and that question too when they was
asking was Adam and Eve created on the
sixth day and formed out of the dust of
the ground. We read that and we
confirmed that. But it's this eighth day
creation doctrine that's getting her all
mixed up. She need to avoid that.
Yeah. So uh brother Buoy explained that.
Yeah.
Okay. Okay, let's move on to our next
question. Yes, next question. Noi
Noi says since Jesus is the lamb of God
that was sacrificed or now this is what
he says was sacrificed on a Wednesday on
the 14th of
Aib. Is it correct to say the 10th
occurred on the Sabbath? meeting Palm
Sunday. Palm
Sunday was actually on a Saturday.
That's the first question he has.
So you want to and the second question
is also would this explain why Jesus
drove out the money changers
afterwards in Matthew 21 verse12 when he
went to the temple because they were
buying and selling on the Sabbath.
So again, the question is since Jesus is
the lamb of God that was sacrificed on a
Wednesday on the 14th of AB, that's what
he says. Is it correct to say the 10th
occurred on the Sabbath, meaning Palm
Sunday was actually on a Saturday?
And again with the money changers. Let's
see. Let's deal with that question first
cuz we asking too if you could please
shorten your question so that we can get
better on it. So um open to the panel.
Well he was he cast out the money
changer because they was polluting the
temple and buying and selling on the
Sabbath day. So he braided a whip and
chased them out of there.
But it didn't but it didn't on the
Sabbath day. So you can't call it the
Sabbath day, right?
They could have been doing that any day.
But but he didn't want them making a
business out of the temple. The temple
wasn't there for for you to buy and sell
and and and uh uh uh
exchange items.
That's right. That could have been on
any day. The violation was that it was
in the temple. Yes. Okay. That's that
Matthew 21, James. Matthew 21, right?
And verse 12. You want me to start at 12
or move up? 12. Okay. Matthew 21 and 12
says, "And Jesus went into the temple of
God, and cast out all them that sowed,
and bought in the temple, and overthrew
the tables of the money changers, and
the seats of them that sold doves." And
said, Go ahead. and said unto them, "It
is written, my house shall be called the
house of prayer, but ye have made it a
den of thieves." And like the guest
caller said, that could have been any
time, but that's what the temple was not
there for, but it's a house of prayer
and worship and praise and they was
doing some illegal stuff in there.
So that's the second question. The first
question is again since Jesus is the
lamb of God that was sacrificed on
Wednesday on the 14th of
AIB. Is it correct to say the 10th
occurred on the Sabbath, meaning Palm
Sunday was actually on a Saturday?
No, it's not correct.
Well, the Bible don't say that. going to
go into Matthew the 12th chapter and
start reading at verse 38. Let you know
that Jesus say was in the in the uh uh
uh grave three days and three nights. Go
read it. Matthew 12 and and verse 38
says, "Then certain of the scribes and
of the Pharisees answered, saying,
Master, we would see a sign from thee."
But he answered and said unto them, "An
evil and adulterous generation seeketh
after a sign. And there shall no sign be
given to it, but the sign of prophet
Jonas." For as Jonas was three days and
three nights in the whale's belly, so
shall the son of man be three days and
three nights in the heart of the earth.
Be three days and three nights in the
heart of the earth. Now I get Daniel's 9
start read from 9 to uh uh 25 to 27.
Let's make sure we know what time that
he called the sacrifices and oblation to
see oblation deceased. That's when he
died on the cross. Okay, go back and
read that. Daniel 9 verse 25-27 says now
therefore or know therefore and
understand that from the going forth of
the commandment to restore and to build
Jerusalem to the unto the Messiah the
prince shall be seven weeks and three
score and two weeks the street shall be
built again and the wall even in
troubles times and after three score and
two weeks shall Messiah be cut off, but
not for himself. And the people of the
prince that shall come shall destroy the
city and the sanctuary, and the end
thereof shall be with the flood. And
until the end of the war, desolations
are
determined. And he shall be cut off.
Going to be cut off, but not for
himself. Now, keep right on. Keep going.
And he shall confirm the covenant with
many for one week. And in the midst of
the weak he shall cause the sacrifice
and the oblation to cease. And for the
overspreading of abominations he shall
make it desolate even until the
consummation and the and that determined
shall be poured upon the desolate. on
the devil. So now how did he make the
sacrifice the oblation and deceased is
when you go and you read in Matthew when
Jesus died on the
cross the veil of the temple ripped from
top to bottom. So there was no no more
places to uh uh uh sprinkle the blood of
the sacrifice and that was in the midst
of the week and the midst of the week is
Wednesday.
So they had to get him off the cross
before the sun down. So that mean that
I'm using gentile term now, not Hebrew
term. So that mean that they had to get
him off cross before that Wednesday
night which we call in the Gentiles
time. You you you understand? And so now
it going to be three days and three
nights. So uh uh like Jonah was in the
well belly so he was they put him in the
ground. He So when the sun went down, he
was in there Wednesday night. He was in
there Thursday night and he was in there
Friday night. And then in the daytime,
he was in there Thursday night. He was
in there Friday night. Uh uh Thursday in
the in the daytime,
uh uh uh uh Friday in the daytime, and
Saturday in the daytime. That's three
days. And he rose before sundown
Saturday. So Jesus rose on the Sabbath
day. had nothing to do with Palm Sunday
which is the first day of the week. He
rose on the seventh
day. That's all I have to say.
Thank you for that. As we move on to our
next question as time is ticking. Yes.
The next question Yura Hadesa Israel
asks, "What are the sure mercies of
David?"
What are the sure mercies of David? Open
to the panel.
Jesus Christ. That's who it is.
Yeah,
indeed. So, uh let's go to Isaiah 55
and3 and then we can expound a little
bit there if anybody would like to to be
able to read those words.
And it's also Acts 13:2, James. But
let's go to Isaiah
55 and three.
Okay. Isaiah 55 and3 says, "Incline your
ears and come unto me here and your soul
shall live, and I will make an
everlasting covenant with you, even the
sure mercies of David."
H.
So we talking some everlasting life
here. That's what you're talking
about. Your mercies of David because the
uh uh because first thing is Jesus came
by through David's
lineage. And the sure mercies is that if
you believe on him, you going to get
eternal life. So sure mercies is
immortality on the right side of the
kingdom. Yes sir. that it's a place to
be. And let's hit it in in Acts 13, too.
Acts 13 and34.
Okay. Acts 13 and 34. 33 and read 33 and
34. Go ahead. Okay. God hath fulfilled
the same unto their children, unto us
their children, and that he hath raised
up Jesus again, as it is also written in
the second psalm, thou art my son, this
day have I begotten thee. And as
concerning that he raised him up from
the dead, now no more to return to
corruption. He said, "On this wise, I
will give you the sure mercies of
David." Yep. So,
and you won't die no more, right?
Yes, indeed. Just keep that word of God
and make your calling and your election
sure. All right, Sister Deborah, we're
gonna move to our next question. Next
question. Mary Higgs asks, "Being that
this Passover is on a weekly Sabbath
this Friday from sundown until Saturday
sundown. Do we need to wait until
sundown Saturday to start cooking for
the feast of unleven bread?"
Yes.
All
right, three letters right there. We
s as we move on to our next question.
Next question. Male Cur says, "I
recently moved into my mother's house
and every and every early mornings I can
hear a voice speaking but cannot
understand what is saying. Is that
possible?
You say you're experienced, so it sounds
like it is definitely possible. Anybody
else want to add to that?
Ain't nobody dispute it and confirm it.
Yep. So, all right, sister Deborah.
Moving on. All right, moving on. be
alert as for you to explain Isaiah 17
verse 10. What is strange slips?
Isaiah 17 and 10. Yes.
And they want to know what
are the strange
slips.
Okay. Let's go and read it and then open
it up to the panel. Okay. Isaiah 17
and10 says, "Hey, James, this don't
sound off too favorable in that first
part of that verse." Go ahead.
Because thou hast forgotten the God of
thy salvation, and has not been mindful
of the rock of thy strength, therefore
shalt thou plant pleasant plants, and
shalt set it with strange slips.
open to the panel on the strange slips.
All that mean you gonna be serving a
strange God because you done forgot your
God.
Shame.
[Music]
All right, Sister Deborah, we coming
down to our last question or two. All
right.
Um, okay. Uh can you ex uh be and be
alert also as can you clarify Isaiah
16:es 3 and 4. Is this during the time
of
tribulation? Why is Israel hiding
amongst
Moab? And that's Isaiah 16 verses 3 and
4.
All right, let's go there, brother, and
read that. Okay. Isaiah 16:3 and 4. Yep.
It says, "Take counsel, execute
judgment, make thy shadow as the night
in the midst of the noon day. Hide the
outcast. Berray not him that wanderth.
Let mine outcast dwell with thee, Moab.
Be thou be thou a convert to them from
the face of the spoiler. For the
extortioner is at an end. The spoiler
ceaseth. The oppressors are consumed out
of the land.
And that question again,
they want you to clarify what that
scripture mean. Oh, why is hiding
amongst Moab? the place of Satan.
It it it said hiding among Moab, but
they on their way to uh uh you know they
they in the wilderness, you know, like
they had to go by Moab, they had to go
by Ammon, they had to go by Edom, but
they on their way to the wilderness
because that's where the Lord is going
to meet him. Read verse one.
Verse one says, "Send ye the lamb to the
ruler of the land from Sahad to the
wilderness unto the mount of the
daughter of Zion."
Why to the wilderness? Because that's
where they going to be. They just going
through there. Go to Ezekiel the 20th
chapter.
Okay.
And we're going to start reading maybe
about 34.
Okay. And Ezekiel 34 says, "And I will
bring you out from the people, and will
gather you out of the countries wherein
ye are scattered, with a mighty hand,
and with a stretched out arm, and with
fury poured out. And I will bring you
into the wilderness of the people, and
there will I plead with you face to
face. Like as I pleaded with your
fathers in the wilderness of the land of
Egypt, so will I plead with you, sayeth
the Lord God.
And I will cause you to pass under the
rod, and I will bring you into the bond
of the covenant, and I will purge out
from among you the rebels, and them that
transgress against me. I will bring them
forth out of the country where they
sjjoin and they shall not enter into the
land of Israel and ye shall know that I
am the
Lord. So now and that's where the Lord
going to meet Israel in the wilderness.
But then you go go in the old days and
look at Israel's travel when they come
out of Egypt. They went through Moab.
They went by Moab. They went by Amar,
you know, and they didn't they would
they wouldn't even let them pass. And
they went by Edom.
Lord say, "Hey, this time when they
coming through, you don't come out
against them. You let them come on
through you on their way to the
wilderness cuz we got to go to the
wilderness just like our forefathers did
when we came out of Egypt."
The place y just let them pass through
you this time. Don't do like your
fathers did in the old days.
That's all I have to say. All right. So,
okay, brother uh Cornell, there's one
more on Passover
that we should get to. Uh question, yes,
the guest caller explained though that
if you are a male, you must be uh
circumcised in order to be uh partake in
the Passover. Uh but she states uh a
brother in truth asked if they could
keep Passover with us, but I explained
to him that you have to be circumcised
to take the Passover according to Exodus
12. He believes that Israelites are no
more no more necess is no more necessary
because of Paul's writing. So she asked
you to break down 1 Corinians 7 18 and
19 and
Galatians. Listen, we're not going to
break that down. We going to go to
Ezekiel and show you what the Lord said
once he returned. Okay. Yeah. Yes.
Ezekiel the 43rd chapter.
You said Ezekiel 47, sir. 44
44 show you that he's coming. He's going
to be on the earth. See, and plus again
too, when Paul made the argument, he was
all about the Gentiles. It wasn't about
Israel. Now, so it was the strangers.
Israel had to be circumcised. That's why
the Lord was going to kill Moses because
he forgot to circumcise his son. This is
Moses, the prototype of Jesus. So now
you being Israelite and you going to try
to use Paul, right? Well, Paul shouldn't
have wrote that about the Gentiles
because the Lord gave circumcision to
everybody. But Ezekiel 43 and I want to
let you know that this is when the Lord
is coming up out of the wilderness. He
is on earth. 43 and1. Go ahead and read.
Then he brought me back the way of the
gate of the outward sanctuary, which
looked toward the east, and it was
shut. Go ahead. Then said the Lord unto
me, "This gate shall be shut. It shall
not be opened, and no man shall enter in
by it, because the Lord, the God of
Israel, have entered in by it.
Therefore, it shall be shut." See, now
this is when the Lord is back on earth.
This during the thousand-y year
millennium millennium period when he
come up out of the wilderness, he going
to come by where the east through the
east gate just like it was when Israel
went into the land the first time. And
he said, "I want this gate shut and
let's see what happened to the Lord."
Where did he go to? Go ahead.
And it it is it is for the prince. The
prince he shall sit in it to the eat
bread before the Lord. He shall enter by
the way of the porch of that gate, and
shall go out by the way of the same.
Go ahead. Then brought he me the way of
the north gate before the house, and I
looked, and behold.
Okay, go
ahead. Read verse four again.
Then brought he me the way of the north
gate before the house and I looked and
behold Wait a minute wait a minute 43
Ezekiel 43 and verse4 yeah he reading
the 44 chapter oh I'm sorry verse
Ezekiel 43 and verse4 says and the glory
of the Lord called the I'm sorry and the
glory of the Lord came into the house by
the way of the gate whose prospect is
toward the east. Now, that's the temple
that's he's talking about. Keep reading.
Let's see what the Lord said. Go ahead
and read. So, the spirit took me up and
brought me into the inner court, and
behold, the glory of the Lord filled the
house. And I heard him speaking unto me
out of the house, and the man stood by
me.
And he said unto me, son of man, the
place of my throne and the place of my
soul of the souls of my feet where I
dwell will dwell in the midst of the
children of Israel forever and my holy
name shall
now if they if he he said this is the
place of my throne and the and the souls
of my feet where I will dwell in the
midst of the children of Israel
forever. Now is he in Israel now? No.
No.
That mean this is all future isn't it?
Yeah. Yes.
Okay. So now let's go into Ezekiel 44.
So Paul went about not circumcise the
Gentiles of the strange. It never was
about Israel. That's why Israel is not
even missing when it come to uh uh
them uh uh uh
uh you know uh uh when it come to the
circumcision after he is back on earth.
Let's start at verse uh uh 6:44 and 6.
Ezekiel 44 and6 says, "And thou shalt
say to the rebellious, even to the house
of Israel, thus sayeth the Lord God, oh
ye house of Israel, let it suffice you
of all your abominations."
Let it suffice you of all your
abomination. What is that? Go ahead. and
that ye have brought into my sanctuary
strangers, uncircumcised in heart and
uncircumcised in flesh to be in my
sanctuary.
Now the Lord now the Lord covered both
areas, didn't he? Yes. People try to see
it circumcised in the heart now. But no,
he said heart and the flesh, didn't he?
Right. Yes, sir.
He read
and in the flesh to be in my sanctuary
to pollute it, even mine house when you
offer my bread, the fat and the blood.
And they have broken my covenant because
of all your abominations.
Huh? They have broken the strangers that
you brought in. That's nonIsraelite.
They done broken my covenant because of
all of whose abomination? Yours. Yours.
That mean that Israel is the one that
told the stranger he didn't have to be
circumcised. But keep reading. The Lord
going to tell you what it says. Go
ahead. Verse 8. And ye have not kept the
charge of mine holy things, but ye have
set keepers of my charge in my sanctuary
for yourselves.
Thus sayeth the Lord God, no stranger
uncircumcised in heart, nor
uncircumcised in flesh, shall enter into
my sanctuary of any stranger that is
among the children of Israel.
Absolutely.
Absolute absolute.
The Lord come and set his sanctuary and
set up on this earth during millennia
period. If you ain't circumcised, if you
are a stranger, a Israelite, you will
not come into his
sanctuary. And I want to go one more
place on this. Let's go into Genesis the
17th
chapter. So the Lord gave us made a
circumcision to everybody, not just
Israel. Israel wasn't around at this
time.
So let's go in uh uh start at verse six.
Okay, that is Genesis 17 and verse 6. It
says, "And I will make thee in
exceedingly fruitful, and I will make
nations of thee, and kings shall come
out of thee, and I will establish."
Mhm. This is fact, come up to uh uh uh
uh uh start at verse one. I want to let
you because this is important to me.
Verse one, read it. And when Abram was
90 years old and nine, the Lord appeared
to Abram and said unto him, I am the
Almighty God. Walk before me, and be
thou perfect.
And I will make my covenant between me
and thee, and will multiply thee
exceedingly.
Now, get down to verse seven, and go
ahead. And I will establish my covenant
between me and thee, and thy seed after
thee in their generations, for an
everlasting covenant, to be a god unto
thee, and to thy seed after thee. He
said in their generation, your seed
after you, that mean in every
generation. Go ahead. and I will give
unto thee and to thy seed after thee the
land wherein thou art a stranger all the
land of Canaan for an everlasting
possession and I will be their God. Go
ahead. And God said unto Abraham, "Thou
shalt keep my covenant, therefore, thou
and thy seed after thee in their
generations."
Uhhuh. This is my covenant which ye
shall keep between me and you, and thy
seed after thee. Every manchild among
you shall be circumcised.
Now see, Abraham is not only the father
of Israel, but he's the father of the
faithful. But he said, "Every manchild
should be circumcised." This is God
telling Abraham this. Now remember, this
is God talking. I don't think Paul is
greater than God. Go ahead and read. And
ye shall circumcise the flesh of your
foreskin, and it shall be a token of the
covenant betw twix me and
you. Huh? And he that is 8 days old
shall be circumcised among you. Every
manchild in your generations, he that is
born in the house or bought with money
or any stranger which is not of thy
seed.
So when he said bought with money of any
stranger that is not thy seed though
that money represent bought with the
blood of Jesus. Go ahead and read any
stranger of th your seed. But go ahead
and read. He that is born in thy house
and he that is bought with thy money
must needs be circumcised. And my
covenant shall
those are two strong words, isn't it?
Must
need must need be circumcised. Go ahead.
and my covenant shall be in your flesh
for an everlasting
covenant. And the uncircum and the
uncircumcised manchild whose flesh of
his foreskin is not circumcised, that
soul shall be cut off from his people.
He have broken my covenant.
Shall be what? Shall be cut off from his
people. He has broken my covenant.
Now cut off mean you going to end up in
the lake of fire. That's it. Yes.
Made this with Abraham and the stranger.
He made it with
everybody.
Everybody. So that mean if you are not
circumcised, you going to be cut off.
What verse is that anyway? That was
verse 14.
Okay.
Go ahead, read some more. And God said
unto Abraham, "As for Sarah, Sarai, thy
wife, thou shalt not call her name
Sarai, but Sarah shall be her her shall
her name be, and I will bless her."
That's enough. I just want to get to the
point where the Lord said, "He, any
stranger, uh, one is homeborn that's not
circumcised,
They going to get cut off from among
their
brethren. Now this is God gave it to
Abraham. If whoever this brother is that
you want if you going to come to the
Israel of God and you drank the blood
and wine and you are not circumcised,
you are drink you you you drink the
blood and and eating the bread and
drinking the blind wine against your own
soul.
So you've been
told if you do it is on you. But Paul
and nobody else can reverse what God
gave to
Abraham. That's all I have to say.
Verse tell you that Abraham and his sons
and and all that were born of money and
the stranger all of them were
circumcised same day.
That covered everybody.
Yeah.
Yeah, there there's one law for all.
That's it. And Ezekiel that this was
here before Paul and Ezekiel the 44th
chapter was here before Paul. They
should have read that.
But it never was
about Israel. We're going to read one
more thing. Let's go into 16th chapter
Acts 16 and and start at verse one.
Okay.
That is
Acts
16 and verse 1 which
says then came he to Derby and List
Listra and behold a certain disciple was
there named Timothus the son of a
certain woman which was a Jewish and
believed but his father was a
Greek which which was which was well
reported by the brethren that were at
Lististra and Iconium. He would Paul he
he would him with Paul have to go forth
with him and took and circumcised him
because of the Jews which were in those
quarters for they knew all that his
father was a Greek.
No, but he had a Hebrew mother. You
understand what I'm saying? Yeah. Was it
because of the Jews? also because he
know too he don't make no error. Israel
was never a question of being
circumcised. The Jews was that whole
thing about not being circumcised was
among the Gentile and the Gentile at
that case was white folks. But the Lord
talked about the stranger that covers
everybody
else. So why did Paul go and circumcise
Timothy? The real thing is because
Timothy had a Hebrew mother. That's all
I have to say.
All
right, we're gonna leave it right there.
As we know that we have ran out of time,
but if we didn't get a chance to answer
your question, please don't resubmit it.
Deborah, take it, put it in rotation,
and we will answer it for you next week.
So until we all come together again,
thank you for tuning in and we ask that
you all be safe, be blessed, stay prayed
up, and may the Lord have mercy on us
all. As brother James closes us
out, our Father, which art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name. Thy kingdom come,
thy will be done in earth as it is in
heaven. Give us this day our daily
bread. And forgive us our debts as we
forgive our debtors. And lead us not
into temptation, but deliver us from
evil. For thine is the kingdom and the
power and the glory forever. In Jesus
name we pray. Amen.
Amen.